[
    {
        "question": "What is the first book in the Bible?",
        "response": "Genesis"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days did God take to create the world?",
        "response": "Six"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first man?",
        "response": "Adam"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Adam and Eve live at the beginning of the world?",
        "response": "Garden of eden"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was God’s sign to Noah that he would never destroy the earth again?",
        "response": "A rainbow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who did God tell to build an ark?",
        "response": "Noah"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days and nights did it rain when Noah was on the ark?",
        "response": "40"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was God’s sign to Noah that he would never destroy the earth again?",
        "response": "A rainbow"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many brothers did Joseph have?",
        "response": "11"
    },
    {
        "question": "Through what did God speak to Moses in the desert?",
        "response": "A burning bush"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two tribes of Israel were not named after sons of Jacob?",
        "response": "Ephraim and Manasseh."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who went up yearly to worship God in Shiloh, and one year prayed to God for a baby?",
        "response": "Hannah"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Melchizedek give to Abram?",
        "response": "Bread and wine"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was to be named Zacharias, after the name of his father, until his mother intervened?",
        "response": "John"
    },
    {
        "question": "When the disciples saw Jesus walking on water, what did they think he was?",
        "response": " A ghost"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Paul with when he wrote the letter to Philemon?",
        "response": "Timothy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the father in law of Caiaphas, the high priest at the time of Jesus death?",
        "response": "Annas"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which missionary was described as having known the holy scriptures from an early age?",
        "response": "Timothy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the name of Abraham's nephew?",
        "response": "Lot"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was king of the southern kingdom when the northern kingdom of Israel fell to Assyria?",
        "response": "Hezekiah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tribe of Israel received no inheritance of land?",
        "response": "The levites"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which angel told Daniel the meaning of his vision of the ram and the goat?",
        "response": "Gabriel"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which book of the Bible do we find Nebuchadnezzar's image?",
        "response": "Daniel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the name of the woman who hid the spies at Jericho?",
        "response": "Rahab"
    },
    {
        "question": "It is “better to obtain wisdom” than what?",
        "response": "Gold"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many requests are in the Lord’s Prayer?",
        "response": "Seven"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who taught the Lord’s Prayer?",
        "response": "Jesus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in the Bible can you find the Lord’s Prayer?",
        "response": "Matthew 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: The opposite of the Fruit of the Spirit are called “the works of the flesh.”",
        "response": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which human author wrote Galatians?",
        "response": "Paul"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who went with Paul on his early mission trips?",
        "response": "Barnabas"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Peter was rescued from prison by an angel?",
        "response": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city were Jesus’ followers first called “Christians”?",
        "response": "Antioch"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Peter raised a woman named Dorcas from the dead.",
        "response": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Apostle shared the Gospel with an Ethiopian official on the road to Gaza?",
        "response": "Philip"
    },
    {
        "question": "I have branches, but no fruit, trunk or leaves. What am I?",
        "response": "A bank"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Apostle took the Gospel to the city of Samaria?",
        "response": "Philip"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many deacons were chosen to help the apostles to distribute food to widows?",
        "response": "Seven"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: Ananias and Sapphira died after lying to the Apostles about their offering.?",
        "response": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who preached at Pentecost?",
        "response": "Peter"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Pilate do to “cleanse himself” of the crucifixion?",
        "response": "Washed his hands"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the Roman Governor who sat over Jesus trial?",
        "response": "Pilate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who gave Jesus a crown made of thorns?",
        "response": "A Roman soldier"
    },
    {
        "question": "What problem did Bartimaeus have that Jesus fixed?",
        "response": "He was blind"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the two Old Testament people who appeared when Jesus was transfigured?",
        "response": "Elijah and Moses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Peter and Andrew doing when Jesus called them to follow him?",
        "response": "Fishing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the demon Jesus cast out in the region of the Gerasenes?",
        "response": "Legion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days was Lazarus dead before Jesus came to visit?",
        "response": "Four days"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was Matthew before he followed Jesus?",
        "response": "Tax collector"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which member of the Jewish ruling council came to ask Jesus questions at night?",
        "response": "Nicodemus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who let the Israelites return to their homeland?",
        "response": "Cyrus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Israelite saved her people from being murdered and was a wife of the king?",
        "response": "Esther"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who returned to Israel to build up the walls of Jerusalem?",
        "response": "Nehemiah"
    },
    {
        "question": "What were Daniel’s three friends (Babylonian names)?",
        "response": "Shadrach, Meshach, Abednego"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happened to the kingdom after Solomon’s rule?",
        "response": "Darius"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who conquered Judah and took Daniel to their country?",
        "response": "Babylonians"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many kings of Israel were there?",
        "response": "19"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many kings of Judah were there?",
        "response": "20"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who convinced Solomon to turn from God?",
        "response": "His wives"
    },
    {
       "question": "How many wives did Solomon have?",
        "response": "700"
    },
    {
       "question": "What did Solomon build for the Lord?",
        "response": "A temple"
    },
    {
       "question": "What trait did Solomon pray for from God when he became king?",
        "response": "Wisdom"
    },
    {
       "question": "During his time as king, who was David’s main enemy?",
        "response": "Philistines"
    },
    {
       "question": "What capital city did David abandon?",
       "response": "Jerusalem"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: The Bible is the most popular book ever written. (by copies sold)?",
        "response": "True"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Moses say God commanded the Pharaoh to do?",
        "response": "Let his people go"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many plagues did God send on Egypt?",
        "response": "10"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did God give Moses the Ten Commandments?",
        "response": "Mt sinai"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
        "response": "Saul"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Jesus' human mother?",
        "response": "Mary"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Jesus’ adoptive father on Earth?",
        "response": "Joseph"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Jesus’ birth father?",
        "response": "God"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the city where Jesus was born.?",
        "response": "Bethlehem"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who baptized Jesus?",
        "response": "John the baptist"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who spoke from the sky when Jesus was baptized?",
        "response": "God"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before Jesus started preaching, what was his job?",
        "response": "Carpenter"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many disciples did Jesus choose?",
        "response": "12"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Jesus do at the Last Supper to his disciples?",
        "response": "Washed their feet"
    },
    {
        "question": "who betrayed Jesus?",
        "response": " Judas iscariot"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Jesus do at the Last Supper to his disciples??",
        "response": "Washed their feet"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which disciple denied Jesus three times?",
        "response": "Peter"
    },
    {
        "question": "What day of the week did Jesus rise back to life?",
        "response": "Sunday"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many books have the name John in them?",
        "response": "Four"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the person who received the 10 Commandments from God?",
        "response": "Moses"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the last book in the Bible?",
        "response": "Revelation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name one book that tell about Jesus' life on Earth?",
        "response": "Matthew"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which book did David write most of?",
        "response": "Psalms"
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False: The Bible was first written in the English language?",
        "response": "False"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the slave traders take Joseph?",
        "response": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many sling-throws did it take David to hit Goliath?",
        "response": "One"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who eventually came from the lineage of David?",
        "response": "Jesus"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many of Jesus’ brothers are named in the Bible?",
        "response": "Four"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Jesus' most famous cousin?",
        "response": "John the baptist"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the shortest book in the Bible?",
        "response": "John"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many books are in the Bible?",
        "response": "66"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many books in the Old Testament?",
        "response": "39"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many books in the New Testament?",
        "response": "27"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which New Testament book has Jesus' Sermon on the Mount?",
        "response": "Matthew"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was David’s son that became king?",
        "response": "Solomon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was most likely the last New Testament book written?",
        "response": "Revelation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who were Noah’s three sons?",
        "response": "Shem, Ham, Japheth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who did God call out of Ur to move to Canaan?",
        "response": "Abraham"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was Abram’s wife?",
        "response": "Sarai"
    },
    {
       "question": "Who was Abram’s handmaid?",
        "response": "Hagar"
    },
    {
       "question": "Who was the first son Abram had? ",
        "response": "Ishmael"
    },
    {
       "question": " What was Sarai’s name changed to?",
        "response": "Sarah"
    },
    {
       "question": "What was the second son Abraham had?",
        "response": "Issac"
    },
    {
       "question": "What were Isaac’s sons’ names?",
       "response": "Jacob and Esau"
}
]
